[Music]
Heat. Hey. Hey.
Hey.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Good evening, good day and welcome back
to the Ask a Widget Show. Today we are
doing episode
248 and I'm going to take questions
about everything that you want to ask me
and I haven't had time to select
questions from the comments. So I'm
going to take all the questions from the
live chat. It's going to be a completely
interactive session today and I'm pretty
sure that you have lots of questions
about Pakistan, about Trump and and
we'll see what else. So let's see who
all is there on the live stream today
with us. I can see Adman Anand
Padmanaba Mahik Kata Geopolitical Dubai
uh Yashwant Sudhir Kai Basant 007
Shakhar Airil Gandhi 74 Vishar Bijes SK
Manoj Prasad 9393 Abi Aush Pand Moria
Ral Bju Ajit Ja Creator GK Amisha Mishra
Shashank Koshik Pratip Reddi Kota
Squidward Gotham Val and Zub
Zubon
easing
indrain surrender sharp subraman
lakshman
again beneath prians sdv siddhant
shashank da um maheshwari bot gaming
rishies samarati sarak mahapatra rishikh
tazupta tan chandra abijit singh god was
alive. Ritik Vishnoi Ritupan Bora Janel
Nirupam Abin Pradan Oscar Madison
Dastanoi God of Kunal Jala Ravi Narayan
Mr. Batsy Crazy Brain Park Jimn Dj Kamat
Truthful Penguin Ashi Ashish Pandel
Insanely Boy Mur
uh Vinay Sahil Vag Shrihari Arun and so
many other people. So, thank you so much
all of you for being on this live stream
with me tonight. And I'm going to stop
greeting you all otherwise that's all
I'll do today. But uh let's get going
with the questions. What questions do
you have? Please ask me your questions
and I'll take as many as I can over the
next couple of
hours. And I have a question by Mark
Levin. IAF used dummy aircraft to fool
Pakistan's air defense system. That's
some deep center of gravity. Well, this
is war. In war you use all means at your
disposal. Uh as Sununsu said all warfare
is about is is a matter of deception. So
if you have the technology, if you can
create fake aircraft, dummy aircraft
which cost next to nothing and have the
Pakistanis have the enemy waste valuable
missiles at those by firing at those
well you should do that and we clearly
are in a position to do that. So we did
that. So outstanding good job. Uh
Prrenip Paul says, "Do you see do you
foresee something massive unfolding in
the next two weeks as part of round two
of operation tendur? Is this the calm
before a decisive
storm?" I don't know. I would love there
to be a part two. We had the Pakistanis
where we wanted them to be but uh they
have kind of slithered away. But if
there's a calm before a decisive story
storm, if this is the calm, then I am
all for it. But uh yeah uh can't really
say can't really say at this point in
time. Duv says was it in the American
interest to uh have a ceasefire to to
ask India to agree to a ceasefire or a
pause in the fighting as India was going
in nuclear exchange would have left no
counterweight for China. I'm not sure
what you're asking but let's consider
the scenario. We are at war with
Pakistan and uh JD Vance goes on a
podcast or interview or something and he
tells the lady I think it was a lady he
tells the lady that you know what this
fight between India and Pakistan it's
none of our business it's none of
America's business we need to stay out
of it that's what JD Vance the vice
president of the US says and in less
than 24 hours Trump comes on social
media says that I have uh mediator he's
fired blah blah blah that sort of thing
Right. Essentially I have forced the two
nations to agree to a ceasefire.
Essentially he has forced India to agree
to a ceasefire. That's essentially what
he's saying because Pakistan was begging
for the ceasefire. So what
changed in those 24 hours and and how is
it in the American interest to uh to
stop India from doing whatever it was
doing to Pakistan? That's the question
you're asking and that's a great
question. So I think the Americans had
never anticipated my friends the extent
to which India would hurt Pakistan. They
thought probably going by historical
precedent that India may do another
surgical strike in Pakistan. Hit some
terrorist outposts a couple of
kilometers from the line of control
perhaps. Or maybe India will do an air
strike, one air strike and we done.
Maybe that's what they calculated. Maybe
that's what they thought.
Right. But what they saw was totally
different. India goes deep inside
Pakistan, hundreds of kilometers inside
Pakistan, hits, I don't know, nine
terrorist camps over and over again.
India doesn't just hit hit those
terrorist camps. India sends loitering
drones to calmly film everything and
then India puts all the evidence uh on
display. So Pakistan is humiliated. So
the Pakistanis try something again. They
try to hit Indian targets with drones
and missiles and whatnot. We bring
everything down. Another gigantic shock
for the Americans and the world. How
does India, a nation like India have the
best air defense system in the world,
better than the Israelis, better than
everybody else? How did that happen? And
when the Pakistanis tried this against
us, we hit them with missiles of all
kinds. The world had never seen what an
Indian missile strike looks like. The
world had never heard an Indian missile,
what an Indian Indian missile sounds
like. And we got to see this from the
Pakistanis, the Pakistani social media,
right? And now we know what an Indian
missile strike looks like and sounds
like. We can hear the missile
coming, but you can't stop it. And we
can see how it sounds and what the
explosion is like. Wham! Right in front
of you. And this happened over and over
and over
again. And then they saw what Indian
drones sound like and look like and what
the explosions are like. It was like we
are hitting them and they are helpless
and defenseless. But that still wasn't
enough. They try again the Pakistanis
they they try to launch a ballistic
missile apparently at Delhi. We brought
it down over Saharana. And once that
missile was brought down by India, the
missile that was aimed at Delhi, that's
when all hell broke loose. I think Mr.
Modi then gave the green light to the to
the armed forces to take the Pakistanis
down in whichever way they wanted. And
then what happens within 30 minutes
India strikes 11 air bases of Pakistan
including the Nurh Khan air base
including Sarodha and so on and so
forth. The Americans had never imagined
I think that India would be able to do
that. India rendered the Pakistanis
completely helpless. Destroyed their air
defenses, wiped out their their radars,
took down their AVAC, one of their AVAC
uh aircraft, cratered all the runways.
The Pakistanis are helpless and they
went begging to the US and they probably
must have threatened the US. We'll use
nuclear weapons. Yeah, you want to try
that? Do you have the means to deliver
them? India takes everything down.
India's air defense works unlike the
Pakistani air defense. So that's where
the Americans stepped in right after all
this happened. Now how is it in
America's interest to prevent India from
destroying Pakistan? Pakistan is
valuable for the Americans. Pakistan is
an entity that has been created for to
serve the western geopolitical interest
in the subcontinent and beyond. This
entire region and Pakistan has been very
valuable for the US in the past multiple
times. Pakistan was the staging base for
the jihad against the Soviet Union in
Afghanistan in the 1970s and 80s.
Pakistan was a staging base for base for
the terrorism against India in Punjab in
the 1980s. Pakistan was a staging bage
base for the terrorism in Kashmir
against India the 1980s, 1990s and all
the way to until now. This terrorism
like the Pakistani defense minister has
said multiple times Pakistan was doing
the dirty work on behalf of the US and
the UK and the
West. Isn't Pakistan
valuable? Who taught terrorism to
Pakistan? how to use terrorism as a as a
as as a tool of state policy. Who taught
this? The Americans did. Pakistan is
valuable. There are times when the
American there have been times when the
Americans have had had no interest in
Pakistan and let the Pakistanis go to
the Chinese for a decade or so. But the
Americans still value Pakistan. Pakistan
needs to keep on existing. If Pakistan
ceases to exist, the whole balance of
power in in the subcontinent region and
and Asia changes completely. and India
becomes way more powerful suddenly. How
can you allow that to happen? So yes, it
was in the American interest to to
maintain the status quo and the balance
of power in the region otherwise India
becomes much larger than they are
comfortable with much more confident
than the Americans are comfortable with.
That's why the Americans saved
Pakistan. All right, next question.
What's question? What's the next
question? Geopolitical Dubai says is
Trump's make in America practically
possible. Are we seeing a typical US
president who wants to remain the sole
superpower? I mean if you are the
president of the sole superpower, you
want the nation to remain the sole
superpower. Why would you want to share
your greatness with others? Why would
you want others to become great? It it
makes no sense for the only hgemon in
the world to want other hammans to pop
up. Why would you want that? It makes no
sense. So he's a typical US president.
Of course he is. and he wants the US to
remain the sole superpower. And if I was
in his place, I would want the same
thing. If I was the president of the
only superpower on the planet, I would
want my nation to remain the only
superpower on the planet. Why will I
want others to to pop up and become
competitors and challengers to my
hgemony? I would not want that. Think
about it logically. So, uh Trump is
exactly that sort of president as he
should be. Every leader needs to look
out for his nation's interest. That's
how the world works. And if he's not
doing that, he's not serving his nation.
He's not doing his job. So he's doing
his job well. Well, or well or not so
well is a different question. But he's
doing his job. So we are seeing that. Of
course, we seeing that and that's what
we should expect. Now is making America
practically possible? A lot of it is not
practically possible because it's too
expensive to make in make in America.
First of all, they have lost the ability
to manufacture a lot of the stuff they
are having manufactured in China because
for decades they had everything they
were relying on China from the 1980s and
90s and 2000s and until all the way
until now. Everything was manufactured
in China. It was much cheaper to make it
in China. So the Americans just moved
their their their manufacturing chains
away from the US and now they've lost
the ability to do all that to replicate
the manufacturing all over again in the
US, you know. And I'm sure with some
given some time they can put it back all
together and start manufacturing
everything once again in the US. But in
the US, manufacturing is way more
expensive than having something
manufactured in the 1990s and 2000s in
China or today in India because the the
daily w the the hourly wages in the US
are way higher than the rest of the
world, much of the rest of the world and
everything is much more expensive in the
US. So it makes no sense for them to
have everything manufactured in the US
because it's going to hurt their economy
very badly. it's going to it's going to
hit uh the common person very badly. So
practically it's very difficult for them
to make this happen. But with the
decoupling the world is seeing with the
bifurcation or the ongoing possible
bifurcation of the world order in which
the half the world will be pro- US and
pro west and half the world will be or
some part of the world will be with
China, Russia etc. and some nations will
be in between. Then when this happens,
you need to bring everything all the all
the manufacturing, all the supply
chains, everything into your with under
your umbrella. So the so the world's
supply chains, the world's manufacturing
chains and
everything is splitting into into
essentially two camps, right? Uh so when
you have the situation, it's going to be
a painful process of decoupling and and
bifurcation and that sort of thing. So
that's what we are seeing. It's going to
be a time of turmoil. It's going to be
turmoil in the US. The people of the US
are going to take financial hits. It's
going to be uncomfortable for them. Many
people will suffer uh financially and in
other ways. But that's just how it goes.
It's a cyclical process in the world.
Chaos and order. Chaos and order. We had
an unreasonably long time of complete
not complete but to a large extent order
in the world. The so-called western le
rules-based world order. But that is a
thing of the past now as you can see. So
there we have it.
Um, Rangers Wolf says, "Trump recently
said that I told Tim Cook we're not
interested in you building in India.
They can take care of themselves despite
India's offer to drop US import
tariffs." Why the disinterest? This is
not
disinterest. Trump is upset with India
for some reason. I think Trump had never
expected that India would hit Pakistan
so badly and so hard. And apparently
when India conducted those air strikes
on the various Pakistani air bases
including air bases that that housed
F-16s and various other American
aircraft it's possible that some
American personnel were affected by
those air strikes because wherever you
have American planes wherever the
Americans have F-16s and other planes in
Pakistan they have a bunch of
babysitters at each air base. You see,
uh, there's a bunch of technicians and
other people at each air base that
houses F-16s, and those people will
never take the F6 will never let the
F-16s off their eyes, off their site.
Okay? They are always there. That's how
it works. If you buy American equipment,
you never really own it. You're simply
leasing it essentially. So, there's a
bunch of people at every Pakistan air
base that has F-16s or other American
planes, and those people are constantly
supervising what's happening. And if you
hit an air base that has American
aircraft, it's possible you may end up
hitting American
personnel. So that's also something that
may have happened and so on. So the
Americans you know they have a certain
they want every nation to play a certain
role as per uh their interests and India
was threaten threatening to to uh get
off the reservation and and not stay in
its lane and we kind of went off
reservation and we we broke the lane
right so that's why the Americans are
upset and that's why Trump is upset and
I think Trump is also upset that India
is negotiating really hard when it comes
to the trade and tariff talks India is
negotiating hard. India is is not
proving is proving to not be a pushover.
So all these things are making Trump
unhappy. He is used to people giving him
a lot of too much respect. He wants
everybody to be super differential to
him and when when he doesn't see that
when when he feels that people are not
sufficiently differential to him he
becomes really upset. I think that's
what's happening with Netanyahu. You see
I think Trump feels that Netanyahu is
not giving him sufficient respect and
that's why the relationship with with
Netanyahu seems to have sed it also one
also hears that Trump is is also
uh uh finding Elon Musk to be a problem
because Elon Musk is more successful
than Donald Trump and Elon Musk is way
richer than Donald Trump and Trump feels
threatened when you have somebody like
that in the in the same room as him. So
Trump is a very sensitive guy. He's a
very egoistic guy. Um and and that's the
sort of character and personality he has
and so if somebody doesn't play the role
he wants them to play, he gets upset. So
right now he's upset with India and the
well that's his problem, not ours,
right? Uh so he he's trying to
pressurize his own companies like Apple
to not manufacture in India. So what's
what's what's it going to be then? Hm.
Do does he want them to go back to China
or is does he see some other nation on
the on the horizon that can manufacture
things at the same scale as India or
China? I think the only nation that can
replace China in the scale at which it
manufactures is India. So it makes sense
for Apple and other American companies
who are looking for alternatives beyond
China. It makes sense for these
companies to manufacture in India. So I
think Trump is just trying to pressurize
India. Trump has a track record of being
a guy who will say one thing today and
say something which is exactly the
opposite of that tomorrow. He displays
zero consistency and he's proud of it.
It's part of his playbook. If you read
his book, The Art of the Deal and if you
go through all the phone calls and
conversations and whatnot he describes
in that book, it's it's just like that.
You know, it's all about putting
pressure on the other guy, pressurizing
the other guy. So that's the game he
plays.
So it's just a passing phase with Trump,
right? And and he's a guy who's
supremely transactional. He will deal
with the devil if need be. If Osama bin
Laden was still alive today, he would
have made a deal with Osama possibly
because until recently the the so-called
president of Syria, Mr. Al- Sharah or
whatever his name is, Julani, that
fellow, he was an FBI wanted terrorist.
There's a poster of the FBI out there
still out there in in the public domain
in which he's wanted and there's a $10
million bounty on his head and yesterday
or day before yesterday Trump posed for
photographs with that guy with that
terrorist with that wanted terrorist. So
that's the kind of game the Americans
play. That's the kind of guy Trump is.
He will make a deal with the devil if it
suits his if it suits uh suits him. So
that's how it is, right? So that's the
kind of president the US has today and
uh perhaps is still better than Biden
for us. So we'll see. Look, at the end
of the day, India is on its own. We are
a nation who has no master. We are not
like Pakistan which is a mercenary
nation. Pakistan always serves foreign
masters, doesn't it? It at times it
serves multiple foreign masters. China,
it serves China, it serves the US, it
also serves Turkey, right? So when you
are a nation like Pakistan who has many
foreign masters
um then lots of people will stand with
you especially people for whom you serve
a certain purpose or especially people
for whom you have a certain value as a
mercenary nation when it comes to India
we don't have any masters so that's why
very few people stand with us in in the
manner that people stand with Pakistan
right but we have way more goodwill in
the world than Pakistan does so that's
how it goes but that's the thing about
Trump you He he will make a deal with
the devil uh if it if it suits him
today. If it suits him today, tomorrow
he'll say it had nothing to do with me.
That's the kind of guy Trump
is. Uh Duv says what's why is Israel
showing affinity towards India despite
openly sponsoring cookie separatists on
their soil? Israel has not supported
cookie terrorism uh openly. Whatever has
been done has been done very very
covertly and maybe there's a lot of
plausible deniability about this. So a
former Israeli ambassador was telling me
what are you talking about when I had
raised the question on on Republic TV
with Arnab I had said that you know some
of this terrorism that's that's coming
into Manipur the cookie terrorism some
of the cookies are getting money from
Israel because there are cookies who
have settled in Israel become citizens
by claiming to be Jews the same people
who eat pork whose whose favorite food
is pork you know so they they have
become Jews they have settled in Israel
they've they've acquired citizenship and
some Some of them are are supporting the
cookie terrorism in India. Some of them
are even possibly even funding cookie
terrorism in India. Right? So I had
raised that issue on on Republic TV a
few months ago and the former Israeli
ambassador was telling me what's the
evidence. So he was playing the
plausible deniability card. Now it's
possible that you know it's possible I
would say that the Israeli government
may possibly have nothing to do with
this. Uh so so it's a complicated
situation. they have genuine plausible
deniability that you know if somebody is
doing it these are private private
individuals it has nothing to do with
Israel state policy that sort of thing
and uh do we have any evidence that it's
Israel's state policy to pro to support
project K cookie land for Christ we
don't have a shred of evidence that it's
Israeli state policy to do that but I'm
sure the Israeli government can kind of
uh have those people tone it down for
example recently the Israeli government
had invited various Indian so-called
influencers to Israel, okay, to to show
what's happening visav Gaza and all that
in the aftermath of the October uh uh
terrorist attack, Hamas terrorist attack
on Israel. So uh apparently one hears
that they brought a cookie rabbi, cookie
ethnicity rabbi to to to put forth the
cookie perspective or something which is
I would say almost blatant and open
interference in India's internal
affairs. So, Israel has had this
undeniable track record. Um, but
overall, if you look at the overall big
picture perspective, so when we talking
about the cookie for Christ project,
project project K and interference in
India's internal affairs and soft
support for cookie terrorism etc. Well,
that we are talking about a subset of of
India, right? We're talking about a
small part of India's far east. Manipur
is a very important state but
geographically it's a small region even
though it's a very important region it's
our gateway to the to the to to
Southeast Asia and so on and the last
bastion of Hinduism in India's far east
and so much more u so it's very valuable
to for us but from a big picture
perspective manipur is a small small
issue many people would say that people
who have no understanding right so from
a big picture perspective Israel's
interests are significantly convergent
with India's interests in in a lot of
ways not in Armenia in that India,
Israel are on opposite sides. So you see
the world is complicated but overall
Israel has had overall the policy of
supporting India and a lot of things and
when it comes to things like Pakistan
and Turkey and all they probably will
will support India even though they are
with Turkey when it comes to Azarba very
complicated world that we live in but if
you understand what goes where then you
will understand why it
works. All
right. Okay.
uh general says currently the entire
population of Pakistan occupied Kashmir
is radicalized. If we take over P in the
near future, don't you think it'll be
held dealing with guerrilla warfare and
human rights groups? I'm sure we have a
contingency plan for
this right. The Americans have a
contingency plan for for Pakistan's
nuclear weapons. It's they have a plan
of what to do in a worst case scenario
where the Pakistani nation breaks up and
the nuclear weapons could very quickly
rapidly possibly fall in the harm fall
into the hands of terrorist groups and
start floating around with terrorists.
What do you do in this scenario? The
Americans have contingency plans for
this worst case scenario. So I am sure
the government of India also has
contingency plans of what to do when in
the future when in a few in a in a
future date Pakistan occupi occupied
Kashmir returns to becoming to becoming
part of India. Uh you know so what do
you do in the situation because we know
that the population is as you rightly
say seriously radicalized. Most of them
probably want us dead. So what do you do
with the population? There must have
there must be contingency plans. Now um
what we should do about this uh I would
rather not tell you in public and uh so
I will say that I I think we should
leave it to the government of India to
deal with this but you're right it's an
issue it's an issue that we should take
very seriously whenever it
happens geopolitical dub says is Trump
receiving gifts from Qatar or is
receiving bribes from Qatar well gifts
bribes potato potato tomato tomato same
thing right uh as as as as a as the
president of of a country or as the
leader of a country, president, prime
minister, whatever, king, whatever it
is, you need to ensure that there are no
conflicts of
interest, right? Your personal interests
uh should stay separate from your
nation's interests. And as the leader of
a country, you have to keep your
personal interests aside and work
towards uh to the the nation's
interests, the interests of the nation.
And I'm sure mostly Trump does that. But
it's also interesting that he has got
lots of personal business interests in
the Gulf region. His family operates
lots of businesses. Uh all his uh close
relatives are involved in a variety of
businesses and those business interests
are front and center in the in in in the
Middle East in West Asia in all these
countries.
And it helps if the president receive if
you if if the president feels happy
about a country because they've given
him a $400
million jet jet aircraft. Right. So
yeah, he has received a gift from Qatar
from the nation of Qatar uh roughly
roughly $400 million uh jet
aircraft. And yeah, if that brings
goodwill, then maybe it's worth the
price. Uh so let's say you give him a
gift worth $400 million but in return
his family interests $40
billion then it's like a 100 times the
the it pays you back a 100 times right.
So if if that sort of thing happens even
if they interest they they they invest
not 40 billion but just 4 billion even
then it's a 10x return on investment.
even if they invest just 1 billion and
you had to spend 400 million for that
that's a 2.5x return on investment. So
I'm sure there are calculations that go
into this and um if you understand how
Trump works then you you can use that to
your
advantage. So that's how it goes in the
world. That's how it
goes. Um Ankita says do you think the
nature of war has changed a lot? Of
course, it has changed significantly
compared to the 20th century. It has
compared
significantly compared to the time of
the Cargill war 1999 or something. It
was, wasn't it? The Cargill war that was
a that was like that's that's a whole
different era, right? Compared to where
we are today in warfighting terms, even
the 2019
uh IndiaPakistan clash, it was very
brief. But even then the way you fought
war today's war fighting methods are
very different from that. A lot has
changed in just 5 years. Uh for the it
was visible for the first time this new
way of fighting war. It was visible for
the first time during the two 2020
Artasak conflict the Nagoro Karabak
latest version of the conflict between
Armenia and Azarbaijan in which
Azarbaijan used a variety of loitering
drones kamikaz drones etc to and they
used it very
effectively and the world stood up set
up and took notice of what was happening
then in
2022 Mr. Putin launched the special
military operation in Ukraine. And then
once again you started seeing so many
different technologies that had that had
never seen the light of day in in in in
a battle space before. But you saw that
you had all kinds of drones, loitering
drones, kamikazi drones, anti- drone
technologies, anti- drone innovations.
put a nest of wires and and and stuff on
top of a tank and it can you know uh
save the tank from the drone to a
certain extent at least save some lives
and possibly save the vehicle and so on.
You saw all kinds of innovations you saw
AI came into the into the field,
robotics came into the field uh drone
warfare came into the field into the
field of battle and so much more. So you
could see the direction in which uh war
fighting was going and I have been
saying for quite some time that India
needs to ensure it's not left behind and
to my utter delight and considerable
surprise we have we have you know
absorbed all the lessons of of uh the
Armenia Abbajan conflict and the Ukraine
conflict and we are actually possibly at
the forefront of the of uh of how this
new way of war is done. So we have used
drones to extremely good effect visav
Pakistan and we have ensured that no
Pakistani drone can can is has been able
has been successful in in hitting an
Indian target. So we have the offensive
as well as defensive capabilities nailed
down. Obviously it's going to have to
keep on evolving because now the world
has seen how India operates in in battle
and now the world will learn and they
will try and find ways of countering it.
So we have it's a cat and mouse game. We
have to keep on evolving, keep on
learning, keep on seeing that now the
world knows that we can do these things.
So let's do something else. Let's
develop some other capabilities. Let's
improve the capabilities and so on. So
the nature of war fighting has changed a
lot.
Um fighter aircraft are
increasingly going to be a last resort
kind of thing. U in the past what used
to happen is that you used to take out
the enemy air defenses using fighter
aircraft possibly or using missiles then
use fighter aircraft for air
superiority. air dominance and today
it's different. Today you start with
drones, you start with missiles, you
neutralize all your enemies air defenses
and other things using drones and
missiles and then when the airspace is
sanitized and the enemy is helpless,
that's when you use fighter planes to to
uh do further strikes. And we didn't see
the next the next iteration of warfare
when you would have an actual physical
infantry advance with tanks or whatever.
And what role drones and fighter planes
uh and missiles will play in in uh uh
you know giving cover to your advancing
uh um armed forces, infantry and
mechanized forces. So we haven't seen
that thus far but I'm sure that we have
all that covered as well. So the nature
is war of war has changed a lot. We also
have other means of fighting war which
is the propaganda war which also
includes uh uh cyber warfare and I'm I I
hear that India is remarkably good at
cyber war cyber warfare capabilities
also we have never demonstrated that but
uh yeah I'm I'm genuinely seriously
pleasantly surprised really surprised
I'm actually quite shocked at how good
uh how well we have uh embraced
the changing nature of warfare and we
have actually surprised the world with
that. Very good to see
that.
Okay. Aish Gupta says does the US have
an alternative nation other than
Pakistan or can any other nation drop
down to the level of Pakistan? Okay, you
asking does the US have other vasal
states u in addition to Pakistan?
Every single member of NATO is a US
vasal state. Every single single member
of the European Union is a US vasal
state. Now what's a vasal state? You may
ask. I use that term a lot. I think I
I'm the one person in the world who has
repopularized the term vasal state. Now
everyone uses that. But I was using it
when no one else was using it. And I I
have I seemingly have popularized the
term vasal state. What does it mean when
I say that so and so nation is America's
vasal state or China's vasal state? What
does it mean? It means so if if you say
that Pakistan is America's vasal state,
it means that America has taken away
some of Pakistan's
sovereignty. Now what does that mean?
What does sovereignty mean? Or if I say
that the UK is America's vasal, it means
that UK has lost sovereignty to the US
to a large extent to a s to a certain
extent. So if if you have a sovereignty
score of 1, it means you are fully
sovereign. But if you have a sovereignty
score of let's say 6, it means you have
lost 40% of your sovereignty. If you
have a sovereignty score of 02, it means
you've lost 80% of your sovereignty.
What does it mean to lose sovereignty?
What does sovereignty mean is the
question now, right? What does
sovereignty mean? Sovereignty means you
have full control over your nation and
everything that happens to it. So what
does it what does it mean to lose
sovereignty? Consider the NATO nations.
When you become a member of NATO, you
sign agreements. You sign an alliance
treaty which and the effect of that is
that you have to hand over control of
your military of your armed forces to
the NATO central command. Now the NATO
central commander the the the overall
head German whatever the director or
whatever it is maybe a German maybe a
Swede maybe a French person maybe a
British person but the real power always
lies with the
US through a variety of means. So if you
become a member of NATO, you lose
control to a significant extent over
your own armed forces and the payoff is
that you don't have to spend so much on
defense anymore. The Americans will
guarantee your
defense. Okay, that sort of thing. If
you become a member of the European
Union, you lose sovereignty in other
ways. You lose control over your own
economy because you no longer have a
currency of your own. you have to use a
currency that's controlled by the by the
EU, central bank or whatever it is. So
you lose control over your economy.
Secondly, you lose control over your
territorial integrity because you no
longer have borders. Your borders are
open. You no longer can control who
comes in and who comes out, right? So
you lose economic sovereignty, you lose
territorial sovereignty, you also lose
political sovereignty because now you
have to accept whatever policies are
framed in Brussels. You can no longer
decide what policies will be implemented
in your nation. Brussels will decide
now. So you lose sovereignty. You become
a vasal of whoever controls the EU, of
whoever controls NATO. In the case of
Japan, they are a vas of the US because
the US physically occupies them. The US
is more than 130 permanent military
bases on Japanese soil. So it's under
permanent US military occupation. Same
goes for South Korea and so on. So and
and when it comes to various African
nations, you can you can turn them into
vasals by simply buying the dictator
that's there. Let's say there is a
military dictator in some small African
nation and the African nation is rich in
resources, copper and lithium and
whatnot. I want those resources. So what
I do is I talk to the guy, the military
dictator. I said that you know what I'll
send you whatever arms you need. You buy
whatever arms you need from me. I'll
give you at a discount and I'll
guarantee your safety and I'll even give
you uh x number of million dollars per
year in bribes and I'll treat you with
respect in the international stage. All
you have to do is open up your nation's
resources to me. I'll plunder them and
you become my guy. So that's how you
prop up dictators all over Africa and
you turn these nations into vasal states
and then you can plunder the natural
national national natural resources and
uh you you get the full complete license
to do that or whatever other thing you
want to exploit from that nation. So
that's how you turn nations into vasal
states. When it when it comes to
Pakistan, Pakistan is useful as a
mercenary nation. they u they are
willing to serve you as a ter as a
terrorist entity for a for a price
that's what they did in the 1970s 1980s
1990s all the way until until very
recently so the US has lots of
alternatives but when it comes to the
Indian subcontinent and the conjunction
of the Indian subcontinent region with
the west Asia region Pakistan is the
only nation in that geographical
location which is why it is very
valuable and indispensable and that's
why uh when it comes to keeping India
off balance and targeting India the US
has no alternative except for Pakistan
and if Pakistan disintegrates or ceases
to exist then the US will lose a very
valuable asset and India will rise
significantly because the whole balance
of power in the region changes and
that's why Pakistan is invaluable can
any other nation drop down to the level
of Pakistan well I'm sure there are many
nations who would love to be as valuable
as Pakistan but let's say East Pakistan
Bangladesh they're trying to they're
trying to play that role but they don't
have the wherewithal to do that because
uh I don't think I mean if if you train
them they also have harbored Pakistani
terrorists in the past they also in the
past when uh that other other individual
woman was in charge
uh khalida zia she was very anti-India
they used to give refuge to Indian
separatists who were either funded by
Pakistan or the US or China they would
give refuge to those Indian separatists
on their soil and they also played such
a role but uh because they don't have
nuclear weapons and all that they can't
rise or drop to the level of Pakistan
and so on. All
right. Uh
okay. Mlebin says the US and China have
agreed to a 90-day truce on the tariff
war. At the same time, India notifies
the World Trade Organization of its
intention to retaliate with tariffs on
the US. Is the US, China, and Pakistan?
Are these three nations joining hands
against India? There's the question.
See, um, the US and China had this have
this ongoing trade war. The US imposed
145% tariffs on the Chinese and the
Chinese retaliated by imposing 125%
tariffs on the US. But while all this
was going on, it looks like these two
nations were negotiating through back
channels. Right? So now they have agreed
all of a sudden to this 90-day truce and
they've brought the titles down to
whatever percentage 15% 20% 25% whatever
it is right so they seem to have worked
things out and they were talking to each
other right
um and uh India seems to be playing
tough with the US and Trump is
definitely not pleased if you try to arm
twist India too much India will
obviously respond in some way in a
reasonable way that's what India is
doing India will possibly if the US if
the Americans recalcitrant if they are
if they are inflexible and if they're
just playing bullying then I suppose
they leave us with no choice but to play
the same game and maybe it'll hurt India
a little bit more than the US or maybe a
lot more we will see about that but u
you can't just let somebody walk all
over you so that's the deal now uh when
it comes to Pakistan
uh the US and China both have an
interest in Pakistan don't they right
it's a nation that that's valuable to
both nations Pakistan is valuable to
China as well the US. Pakistan has in
the past rendered services given
services to both China and the US and as
such it's a valuable nation. So it looks
like I think it's a possibility we have
to consider that there is a possibility
that as part of this deal that the
Americans the Chinese have struck this
90-day truce and further negotiations
that deal it's possible they have also
had this understanding that we need to
safe to safeguard Pakistan's existence.
We need to ensure that Pakistan keeps on
existing because it is valuable to both
of us, you know. So, it looks like the
Americans and the Chinese see eye to eye
when it comes to uh Pakistan and the
need for Pakistan to continue existing,
right? And it's possible that the
Chinese may have told the Americans that
if you want uh us to agree to some kind
of deal with you, then maybe you need to
throw India under the bus. you know it's
possible all these things are
possibilities it's possible that these
things happened behind the scenes so uh
yeah that's what I can say it's possible
that they are joining hands against us
to a certain extent it's it's definitely
possible right
um uh there's a question that's not over
here on the live chat it's by professor
Gautam Di Raju a very learned gentleman
he's asked a question u can bhat
leverage with China against the US with
respect to trade matters after all they
are adversary countries u and that's a
very interesting question that professor
diiru has asked and obviously he himself
is a very learned man and it's an honor
that he has asked this question to me so
can India leverage China with respect to
the US because with respect to trade and
other dimensions because After all, the
US and China are adversary nations. Uh
it's certainly something we can explore.
Like the Americans and the Chinese were
fighting each other publicly while
having backdoor conversations clearly
all these days. Uh it's certainly
something we can explore. The Chinese in
the past year and a half or so have
tried to explore the possibility of some
kind of the orromo with India uh because
they could see the American onslaught
coming towards them. Right. Um and even
now if they have some kind of
understanding with the US for the time
being for the next 90 days and even in
the future if they consolidate some kind
of agreement with the US the US is still
going to go after China they're going to
deny them technology they're going to
try and hurt China in various ways and
so on. So it makes sense that if the
Americans are
um are supporting Pakistan against India
it makes sense for us to explore options
with China as well. Now we have to
always remember that China is not a
friendly country to the to to us. We
have to always remember that if the
Chinese are given an opportunity they
will want India to fail very badly. But
as long as you don't give them the give
them that opportunity and you deal with
them from a position of strength then
it's possible to have some kind of
understanding with the Chinese and some
kind of uh trust but verify level
cooperation with the Chinese. The
possibility exists for
sure, right? So, we will have to
approach the Chinese and deal with them
from a position of strength. Now, the
Chinese will be very surprised at at our
performance in that 3-day war with the
Pakistanis. They'll be very surprised
and actually very upset that we were
able to bypass the Chinese radars,
destroy the Chinese radars and render
them useless. and we were able to uh you
know nullify the so-called advantage the
Pakistanis had of using long range
Chinese missiles and they'll be very
concerned about this and they'll be very
surprised at the performance of India's
multi-layered air defense system and
they'll be very concerned about this air
defense system also being present in the
along the India Tibet border the the
undemarcated border so the Chinese will
begrudgingly be a little more respectful
towards India know they will try and not
show it but inside they'll be concerned
and the only way you can gain someone's
respect if they if is if they fear you
to a certain extent and the only way you
can get gain China's respect is if they
fear you to a certain extent and now
they certainly will have a little more
fear as as compared to the past about
India so you can leverage that you can
use that to your advantage and explore
the possibility of some kind of issue
based cooperation with the Chinese let's
say on certain economic uh uh domains
and so on. It's something that is uh
definitely worth
doing. Okay.
Um geopolitical dub says hypothetically
asking what if US makes Pakistan a NATO
member? Well um North Atlantic Treaty
Organization and the Indian Ocean region
that would be a very strange thing but
what if the Americans do that? See first
of all there are certain conditions a
nation has to meet to become a member of
NATO. I don't think Pakistan meets those
conditions and uh if you want to become
a member of NATO you have to pass
certain tests and uh you know align with
certain guidelines and all that. There's
a whole playbook at play that comes into
play when a nation applies to become a
member of NATO and I don't have the
documentation with me right now over
here but you have to abide by those
conditions and you have to raise your
standards to a certain level before you
become a member of NATO. I don't think
Pakistan is capable of doing that of
becoming a member of NATO based on the
on the on the on the conditions that
currently exist. What the Americans have
done to Pakistan is they've made it a
major non-NATO ally which is the next
best thing. So it doesn't matter what
tag you put on a nation as long as the
Americans favor Pakistan and and have
some use for it, it works fine for the
Pakistanis. Uh the Strummer says why are
the defense forces not clarifying the
status of Rafals? Have we really have we
really lost them? How the hell do you
care? Why are we so concerned about what
the Pakistanis are claiming?
H the defense forces, the armed forces
have said that you know losses are a
part of battle. They have not said we've
lost
Arafal in 2019. We lost a Mig 21. We
lost a helicopter which we we ourselves
shot down recently in the fighting
against the Houthis. The Americans lost
some F18s or whatever. They almost lost
a F-35. These things are part of
warfare. But Indians are obsessed with
these things. If we lost an aircraft
here or aircraft there, it means we have
lost everything. I just don't get why we
are so obsessed with these
things. Let's say we lose an aircraft
here or there. Have you seen what we did
to the
Pakistanis? I'm not saying we've lost
the Rafal. I'm I just don't get why
Indians are obsessed and there are keep
on harping on this thing. Move on. We
beat the Pakistanis black and
blue and in case hypothetically we lost
X one of this aircraft or one of that or
whatever hypothetically how does it
matter for
you? I'm I'm this is that nitpicking
habit of Indians that is so detrimental
to to
themselves. Indians want to criticize
India. Indians want to find fold with
India all the time.
The armed forces should not clarify
anything and leave people like this
hanging because it's not it doesn't
matter in case we have hypothetically
lost something we will replace
that you know what's important for the
military the trained personnel are
important the amount of time it goes
into training one top quality fighter
pilot you cannot measure that in with
with money it's it's worth billions of
dollars. It's worth the 20
Rafal. So I don't know. I have seen zero
evidence that any Rafal has come down or
or any Rafal or any other fighter plane
has been destroyed. In today's day and
age of social media where you can't hide
a
thing, you saw all the coverage of all
the all the all the missile strikes and
drone strikes in Pakistan. You think the
Pakistani military wanted all that to
come out? Well, it came out. You can't
hide a thing today. So if a Rafal or
another some other aircraft fire fighter
plane
hypothetically was shot down let's say
over Pakistani territory or Pakistani
occupied territory it would have been
all over media didn't happen right but
if it had happened in India don't you
think it would have come out don't you
think people with cell phones would have
shot it and put it on social media it's
impossible to hide that nothing has
happened but Indians will keep on
harping about this what the defense
process should clarify The prime
minister should said
that. I'm just tired of this really.
Indians are their own worst enemies.
Seriously, I just I just don't get
it. I just don't get
it.
Um, okay. Aditya Kumar Shaw says they
clarified recent document of operation
Sindor clearly states that no Indian
assets are lost but Indians will not be
will will not be satisfied with this.
Some Indians want Indian Indian assets
to be lost because Pakistan said that,
right? Because Syrian said that because
the white man said it, that's why
something must have happened. Indians
have this incredible inferiority
complex. When the white man says
something, it has to be
true. Well, has the white man been able
to show you evidence of India having
lost a so and so asset? Have they been
able to show you a shred of evidence?
When you make a claim without evidence,
you are lying. When you make a claim,
the onus is on you who are making the
claim to produce the
evidence. It's not on me to pro to show
evidence that proves your claim. To hell
with you, Mr. CNN. If you make a claim
claim, you produce the evidence. They
have produced no evidence. But Indians
say that no, the white man said this,
right? So, he must be right. So, we are
hiding something. This is the loser
mentality of Indians.
This is the mental colonization. This is
the inferiority complex so many Indians
have and it and it it infuriates me no
end. What can I
say? Pranet says how should India brace
for the next stage of operation zindur?
Is balkcanization of matter of Pakistan
a matter of time or are we heading into
a long war of attrition both military
and psychological? The bulcanization of
Pakistan is a matter of time.
uh when the time comes even the
Americans not even the Americans will be
able to stop us from bulcanizing
Pakistan I think it's a matter of time
maybe 3 months maybe 6 months maybe 3
weeks maybe 3 years at most at most 10
years Pakistan I would say like I said
with the pahalgam attack the the the
countdown started for Pakistan the clock
is ticking it's ticking backwards it's
ticking towards zero I'm not sure when
zero arrives but it's going to arrive
soon what about operation sindu
I think operation sundur is pased is
paused for now. That's what the prime
minister has said that we have paused
operation sindur. That's what
drashamantri has said Mr. Rajnat Singh
we have paused operation
sindur the operation is not over. Uh so
we will have to keep an going to keep an
eye on the behavior of the Pakistanis
and if they you know do any more base
adventures the operation resumes and uh
next time is going to be they're going
to be hit even harder. Um
uh so we of course we in India need to
be very careful. The Pakistanis are a
terrorist nation and they have been
humiliated despite claiming whatever
they're claiming they have been
humiliated. Their ar their their air
force their personnel will never forget
what happened to them. How they were
rendered utterly helpless while India
while Indian aircraft flew repeated uh
sorties over their their their
uh runways because the runways were
crippled and uh they lost some personnel
as well and some personnel apparently
from Turkey also have been lost and so
on.
So I think it's a matter of time that uh
Pakistan is dealt with once and for all
whether the Americans like it or not. I
don't think we are heading into a long
war of attrition. A long war of
attrition is like the Ukraine conflict.
It's a slow war scenario. It's a long
war scenario right now. It's just
dragging on. We are not going to be
drawn into that.
Um we have we will have to be careful
about potential uh Pakistani
misadventures not military but terrorist
misadvent misadventures against India.
It is
possible considering the Pakistani
psyche and their track record that they
may attempt to launch terror attacks on
Indian targets not on the border but
inside India. It's possible. So we're
going to have to be cognizant of this
fact and we're going to have to prepare
accordingly in our major cities and so
on. And if something happens, it should
be the end of Pakistan whether Mr. Trump
likes it or not. And I think we are very
capable of putting an end to Pakistan in
24 hours after what we have seen. We
were we treated them with kid gloves in
that 3-day war. We could have hit them
with with a 100 times more missiles.
It's even possible that the warheads we
used in the missiles were not were not
very powerful. We could have used much
more powerful warheads. I I assure you
we have warheads that are way more
powerful than what we have used. I'm
talking about conventional warheads. I'm
not talking about nuclear warheads. We
should no civilized person talks about
nuclear war unless he's a Pakistani when
then you're not civilized. So that's how
I see it.
Yeah.
Okay. Tanay Chandra says, "Will the
Armenians be very happy as they have
bought the Paka and the Akash air
defense systems?" So the Akash system is
an air defense system and the Paka is an
offensive offensive system. It's a
multiarrel uh rocket launcher system
that launches those those huge salvos of
100 missiles at the rockets at the same
time and it essentially is used to
sanitize a certain u square kilometers
of territory. Right? So that's what the
Paka system does. The Akash
surfaceto-air missile defense system.
Whoever has bought it must be really
really happy because the real superstar
was the Akash system and the L70 system
and the whole overall integrated Indian
air defense system of which Akash is a
very important
component. So the Akash system has
turned into an overnight superstar. It's
you can't bypass Akash. Akash will get
you right. So whoever has bought Akash
which is Armenia of course they will be
super happy about this and their arch
enemies the Azaraijanis are going to be
are going to be worried now are going to
be worried the Akash can take you down
whether you're a fighter plane whether
you're a helicopter or whatever else you
are Akash will take you down so yes uh
good that the Armenians will be happy
about this that their confidence will
have risen and I think there's going to
be a significant demand now for the
Akash system and we can sell it to to
friendly nations
certainly.
Um, okay. Uh, Page Singh says, "Taking
into account the fact that Turkey sent
its warship to Pakistan. If in another
wartime if in another wartime situation
they aggressively attack us in the
Arabian Sea, will NATO article 5 be
enforced if we
retaliate? I think we can retaliate and
not worry about NATO article 5. NATO
article 5 says that an attack on a NATO
nation a member state of NATO is to be
seen as an attack on the o on the of on
every other NATO nation right so are we
attacking Turkey the the territory of
Turkey if we take out a Turkish warship
that's attacking us in the Indian Ocean
let's not call it the Arabian Sea I
would call it the Sea of Sarah it's not
the Arabian Sea it's part of the Indian
Ocean so if they launch an attack on
India, the Turks. Okay, hypothetically
in the Indian western Indian Ocean
region, we will wipe it wipe the uh that
uh warship down. We'll wipe it out.
We'll slice it into two with a bramos.
I've shown you in a previous live stream
what the bramos does to warships to two
ships. It just slices ships into two.
So, we will do that to them. And if they
if they started the whole thing, how can
NATO blame us, right? And we not
attacking Turkey. It's not an attack on
Turkey. It's an attack on an on a
hostile warship which may belong to
Turkey. That that's their problem. I
don't think the Turks would be stupid
enough to do any such thing first of all
visavas. They're simply uh doing the
playing that old game right words versus
actions. By sending a warship to
Pakistan, you giving verbal support
essentially. It's actions only if the
warship is deployed against India in
active warfare. And the Turks won't dare
do that because we will destroy their
warship. They know it. Now everybody
will be worried about India's
capabilities. We've only shown
capabilities in one domain which is the
air especially air defense and of course
we've shown capabilities when it comes
to drones and in taking out Chinese
radars and air defense systems. So we
have shown a small subset of our
capabilities but now the world will be
wondering what other capabilities will
these Indians have. They'll be really
worried
now. So if Turkey wants to play with
fire, well they are welcome to. I
welcome you to play with fire.
Right. Uh Shrea says, "Is this the right
time to implement CA and NRC by creating
a record of all citizens who are legally
here and deport the illegal ones and
prevent terror outfits and sleeper
cells?" I think if we if we can deport
all the foreigners who are squatting on
Indian terri territory, whether they are
Rohingya, whether they are cookies,
whether they are Pakistanis, whether
they're Bangladesh, we should deport
them all. identify each and every one of
them and deport them all. That will take
away a huge shadow of terror from from
from our citizens in our in our in our
country. Right? When you have said
foreigners living in your
territory, exploiting your
resources and essentially terrorizing
your population and these these people,
these foreigners have absolutely no
affinity with or allegiance to your
nation or your culture or civilization,
then they're going to be a problem. And
if they have come into India illegally,
they should be thrown out. It's as
simple as that. It's high time the
government of India does this. I think
the the war this three-day war with
Pakistan is is given them the best uh
cause the best excuse or whatever you
want to call it to implement this and if
the world has a problem with the with
with what we are doing then the world
can the world be damned it's a matter of
our national security our national
interest I think it's high time we do it
I think I'm seeing some action on that
front finally we need to make it happen
fast imagine a 100 million Bangladesh is
God knows how many tens of thousands of
Pakistanis a few I don't know how many
hundreds of thousands of cookies how
many hundreds of thousands of Rohingyas
what the hell are we a nation or are we
a
joke deport all illegals at the earliest
needs to happen
um Mr. 80ers says are we going to see
some cracks in the Modi Modi Trump
relationship you
see whenever Mr. Trump tweets about
India, Mr. Modi makes it a point to very
quickly, very rapidly respond to that
tweet with a great amount of
warmth. Right? Mr. Modi has always made
a point to do do that. And this time
when Mr. Trump tweeted about India, Mr.
Modi ignored that
tweet. When Mr. Modi gave his address to
the nation, he did not mention the US.
He did not mention Mr. Trump's name.
So I think we already seeing it. Is it
Mr. Modi's fault? Is it India's fault? I
think Mr. Trump has only himself to
blame for this. If he thinks he can play
this game, then you know what? Nobody
will trust him. I he he definitely
suffers from a lack of trust. No one
trusts him because of his his behavior,
his unpredictable behavior, his his
vacasillating
behavior, right?
extremely unreliable person which makes
you untrustworthy. Nobody will trust
you. Obviously everybody wants to be on
his good side. Everybody wants to be
differential to him. Everybody wants to
be nice to him. Everyone wants to give
give him gifts. Some would give him fire
what jet jet aircraft and whatnot. But u
he's not seen as a reliable person
because of the way he operates extremely
transactional. So it's entirely their
problem. Entirely their problem,
entirely his
problem. Uh Arjun Bondapadaya says, "How
probable is war without the full if
squadron strength?" It helps to have the
full squadron strength, whatever it is,
32 or 38 squadrons, whatever. I don't
know how much we have
today, but we seem to have done the best
we can considering considering that gap
in our
capabilities. I would love to have twice
the number of fighter planes we have
today. But let's say we are currently in
a situation where we don't have the
number that we want. Then sometimes you
have to not sometimes you have to be
realistic and say okay I have this
deficiency here. How can I best cover it
up? So we have we are covering it up by
increasing our offensive capabilities in
other ways which would typically have
been covered using fighter planes. So we
have shockingly dangerous missiles. We
have shockingly efficient uh drones,
offensive drones and so on. So we have
kind
of you know balanced that out with the
other offensive capabilities that we
have developed.
So, so we should keep we should continue
bolstering our missile strength, getting
more missiles into the stockpile. We
should have a stockpile of tens of
thousands of missiles. Actually, we
should also have a stockpile of maybe
tens of thousands of drones in the
meanwhile. Doesn't hurt if
we reugment the number of fighter planes
that we have over the next five, six
years. So, how probable is war? I think
if you are dangerous, if you are scary
and if you have
uh capabilities that that scare your
adversaries, then war is less
probable, right? But we're talking about
a rational actor here. Pakistan is not a
rational actor. So you may have war
again in the next two weeks. Who knows?
It's a possibility. If they try a
terrorist attack against India
somewhere, then the then war is again
guaranteed if they do that. So we will
again then hit at terror camps and
infrastructure within Pakistan if
there's a terrorist strike on India and
given Pakistan's track record and
Pakistan's psychology psyche and nature
I think it's a matter of time before
they try something obviously I will very
much hope that if they try something we
foil that attempt but even the the fact
that they're trying something means that
they want war so we'll
see Shastri says, "How 14 mark S500
intercepts 20 mark nuclear ICBM in
midair." The S500 and its capabilities
are pretty secretive, pretty classified.
The S500 is the next generation of the
S400 system. And the S400 is the next
generation of the S300 system. There's
an S350 also, I believe, and possibly an
S200. So it's a next generation kind of
augmentation iteration of the system.
You know the system keeps evolving gets
getting better and when there's a
significant improvement they call it the
next number. So the X500 the S500 is
possibly capable of taking down
ballistic missiles possibly and
definitely cruise missiles and other
aerial threats. That's what one hears
but nobody has actually seen it in
action. Nobody knows actually what it is
capable of. It is rumored that it can it
can probably take out ballistic missiles
and other things. We don't know how fast
its missiles fly. I don't know if it's a
Mac 14 missile that one of the missiles
that it it has. It's possible the
fastest Russian missile that we are
aware of is the Circon missile which for
a certain probably for the terminal
phase has a mark 9 speed which is nine
times the speed of sound probably for
the terminal phase phase maybe for a 100
seconds or maybe 200 seconds or
something like that not sure what the
exact number is so it's a it's a
partially hypersonic missile it's
hypersonic at the end when it's going to
hit the target that's the circon missile
that's mark 9 do the Russians Mark 14
missile. I'm not sure. Maybe they do,
maybe they don't. I don't know. It's
classified. Uh ICBMs. Look, a nuclear
ICBM is not different from a regular
ICBM. An ICBM is ICBM. And the the speed
of an ICBM is what you call re-entry
speed because it it it follows a
parabolic
path. Um projectile motion. You'll learn
that in in high school in physics. So it
follows a present parabolic trajectory.
It it rises up, it exits the atmosphere,
then re-enters atmosphere and it it hits
the target at close to re-entry speed
which is around 20 possibly 25 times the
speed of sound. Maybe by the time it
comes all the way down it speed may
reduce to a certain extent depends okay
we don't know the exact characteristics
unless you are working on the system
yourself. So let's say it's mark 20 new
ICBM you can take it down if you know if
you if you have a track on it of it on
the radar or through other other systems
and you can see it trajectory you can
calculate where it's going to come and
what path it's going to take. Uh so 20
times the speed of sound is is I'm sure
it can be done uh through if you have
good technology. For example, if you're
taking out an ASAT, if you have an ASAT
system, anti-satellite system,
anti-satellite weapon that you use to
take out a satellite in Earth's
orbit, that weapon, the kill vehicle,
the terminal phase of the system needs
to be able to hit a satellite that's
traveling at about 10
km/s relative to where you launch the
missile from. 10 km/s, what's the mark
number?
So mark 1 is 333
m/s,
right? So that's mark 1. 10 * that is
3,330 m/s. That's 3.3 km/s. That's mark
10. Mach 20 is
6,600 m/s. So Mach 10, sorry, Mach 20 is
6.6 km/s.
Mach 20. But the
ASAT weapon that we have, it can take
out a satellite which is 10
kilometers/s. So that's mark
2526. Imagine that. It's possible. As
you can see, we we have the technology
to take out an object that's that's
traveling at essentially mark
2526, give or take. Very possible. Very
possible. So technology, if you have it,
it's almost like
magic. These objects are are are moving
faster than speeding bullets, flying
bullets. Way faster. And yet you can
take them out. There you have it,
friends.
Uh, fund restored. I like the name fund
restored says, "What should India do in
manufacturing jet engines? like should
we go with R&D and or just spend hefty
money to buy tech to manufacture as per
the current situation. I think we should
take both approaches. Whoever is willing
to transfer the full jet engine
technology including the turbine blades
and so on whatever it costs pay it and
buy it and acquire the technology. At
the same time, we should continue our
indigenous
R&D at the gas turbine research
establishment and wherever else it may
be
happening, buy the technology also
develop it
inhouse. That's what needs to happen. It
has to be a twopronged approach. So
let's say we get
lucky and we are able to let's say buy
the technology for let's say $10 billion
a huge amount of money. Does it mean
that if we now have the technology,
we've bought it and we are able to
replicate it. Does it mean that we
should stop our own research and
development process, R&D process? No, we
should not stop it. We should continue
that as well. And maybe we should
transfer some of the learnings from the
technology we acquired into that. But
don't stop that process. That's what we
need to do. Both approaches should
continue at the same time
simultaneously. That's what India needs
to do.
Churag says even after becoming a 10 to1
15 trillion economy Pakistan can attack
again attack and play the nuclear card.
How does this cycle end? How about using
anti-satellite to destroy their news
propaganda?
Okay, first of all, um, yeah, you are
right, Churag. Even if we become in the
future, when we become a 10 trillion
dollar economy, when we become a 15
trillion dollar economy, as long as
Pakistan is sitting next door, it's
going to
be a problem for us. It's going to it's
it's it's like having a parasite, a
vampire attached to you. It's like
having a permanent cancer that keeps on
poisoning you, right?
As long as they exist next to you, there
will always be a problem. So the only
way to be break free of this is to break
Pakistan into pieces to balconize
Pakistan. That's the only way to do it.
That's the only way to permanently end
this
headache. Right? So we have to we need
we need to have a new special military
operation or something against Pakistan.
The objective should be the
bulcanization of Pakistan and the
denuclearization of Pakistan and it
should be done by us. So eventually
we're going to have to do it. That's the
only way the cycle ends. Uh when it
comes to the news propaganda, the
propaganda doesn't come from
satellites and you can't just randomly
start shooting down satellites. Pakistan
doesn't even have
satellites. I mean they may have one,
maybe two, but that's not the propaganda
machine. The propaganda machine that
supports Pakistan is the Western media.
It's CNN. It's whoever else. It's the
BBC and whoever else pedals Pakistani
propaganda and and uh and augments
Pakistani perspectives, narratives,
lies. That's the propaganda. You can't
these are human beings. These are
individuals. These are journalists.
These are writers. These are news
readaders and so on. You can't use an
anti-satellite weapon to target those
people. Right? So that's not how it
works. The propaganda is is is not
coming from satellites. It's definitely
not coming from coming from Pakistani
satellites. It's the West that is upset.
It's the West that wants to make the
world believe that Pakistan has done
well in this in the three-day 3-day war.
And why does the west want the world to
believe that Pakistan has done well and
India hasn't done so well and Pakistan
has been excuse me Pakistan has been at
least the equal of India in the
war. Why does why does the west want the
world to believe this? Tell
me it's because
India has either Indian weapons
atbar home manufactured weapons like the
Akash system and whatever else or we
have French weapons possibly which is
the Haval or we have Russian weapons and
if we have succeeded it's by using a mix
of these three Indian Russian and French
weapons and the US doesn't see France as
a with with a great deal of warmth and
friendliness. Okay. There there is
tension between the US and France, it
always it's always there below the
surface. So if India uses French,
Russian and Indian weapons and they turn
out to be superior to Western weapons,
American weapons and Chinese weapons,
it's a problem for the Americans. Look,
they even don't like India Indian
weapons being better than Chinese
weapons because China is a clear and
present threat and the whole world
recognizes China as a
technological near superpower. But if we
have weapons that are better than
Chinese weapons, then we have a big
problem for the from their perspective,
they have a big problem on the horizon.
There's a new power that's emerging with
the
technology with the ability to to to
develop technology that is better than
western and Chinese technology.
right their own want see and and and if
the world starts recognizing that then
India becomes more confident and the
Indians who crave validation from
western people they also become
confident so let's not most Indians have
an inferiority complex most Indians are
are mentally colonized most Indians if
the white man says that the three Rafals
went down or 78 Indian UFOs went down
the Indians will start questioning their
own own army right so let that happen
bring the morale of the country down
that's the propaganda war that's being
unleashed against India at all times
during the Ukraine war during the 3-day
India Pakistan war and so on the west
will always take the other guy's side
right so you can't use anti-satellite
weapons to de to destroy that propaganda
do you understand you have to counter
their fake news narrative with your own
true news narrative that's how it
works all right um
Ina says uh Dr. SJ Shanka said that we
informed Pakistan at start of operation
Sindur. Isn't it stupid? What we
informed Pakistan at the start of
operation Synindur? Isn't that
stupidity? What's my perspective point
of view? Did our foreign policy fail
because nobody took a firm stand for us?
Look, I don't know what the media is
reporting.
I I saw some some kind of tweet some
time ago and lots of people are now
raising this objection and raising this
point that why that apparently it looks
like apparently the the the tweet and
the news snippet is is quoting Dr. J.
Shankar as having said that we told
Pakistan at the beginning of operation
zindu that we are hitting terrorist
camps. I don't think India did such
thing. Just like Donald Trump said that
I have mediated between between India
and
Pakistan and India and Pakistan have
agreed to hold talks and negotiations at
at a neutral venue. That's what Donald
Trump
said. But the truth is he has done no
such thing and India and Pakistan have
not agreed to hold negotiations at a
neutral venue. That's fake news, right?
So similarly sometimes you can tell
lies if required. It doesn't mean that
you actually did
that. So please understand the
difference between words and actions in
diplomacy, in international relations
etc. You can use words to your
advantage. You can you can use words to
create a certain
narrative. You can use lies to create a
certain narrative. Now India's moto is
saty jay which is a really stupid mo mot
mo mot mo mot mo mot mo mot mo mot mo
mot mo mot mo mot mo mot moto
actually because no Indian follows that
moto most Indian politicians do the
opposite most not all but most right and
the world doesn't work on the principle
of satyavj you have to lie a lot of the
times in the world especially when you
are serving your national interest so
Trump clearly lied about the claims that
he made so why can't we lie sometimes I
think it's possible that we are playing
with words and possibly uh pushing the
boundaries of what is true and what is
untrue to make to create a certain
narrative. It's
possible. So why are we attacking our
own foreign minister? We won the
conflict, right? I don't do not believe
for one second that India telephoned
Pakistan and said that you know what in
5 minutes we're going to launch attacks.
If we had done that the attacks possibly
would have failed. Don't you don't you
people have that much understanding that
if we had told the Pakistanis even 5
minutes before we launched the attack on
the terrorist camps then the Pakistanis
would have scrambled their fighter
planes and you know done whatever they
could and maybe our loitering drones
which calmly took the videos of the
strikes maybe they would have been shot
down. So maybe we are using the good old
words versus actions game. Maybe we are
putting out f false news, fake news.
Maybe we're trying to create a certain
narrative for the world's consumption.
Let us not get all
hyperactive about these
things. We know that the Pakistanis have
been lying about a lot of things,
right? Why can't we lied sometimes? Why
why do we have to always speak the
truth? Can't we all be a little more
mature in the pursuit of the national
interest? It is okay to lie if
required. Something that is worth
fighting
for. It is worth lying for. It is worth
fighting dirty
for.
Please develop some more
maturity. Right?
Please. Words versus actions. We took a
certain set of actions and now we are
saying some
words. The actions are done. Now let's
play the game of words. If required,
let's mislead the world in the pursuit
of our
interests. So
I I know lots of Indians right now
asking, "Oh, Janka did this, Janka did
that. We should have done something
else." Please grow the hell up,
children. What are we third standard
kids
here? Uh Aris Manticor says, "Pakistanis
raised their kids to hate the existence
of India." Unfortunately, it's true.
While we raise pigs for slaughter who
are un unaware of the nefarious
intentions of our neighbor, an Indian
YouTuber was brainwashed by the ISI
recently. Yeah. You know what can I say?
Indians Indians are super naive. Indians
are super gullible. Indians crave
external validation. Indians have an
inferiority complex. I think even some
Indians even have an inferiority complex
with the Pakistan.
There are many Indians who think that
Pakistanis are more handsome than us.
Pakistanis are taller than us.
Pakistanis are stronger than us and so
on. I just can't get how
incredibly mentally colonized Indians
are. How much of an incredibly
inferiority complex Indians have and
such people are so easy to
manipulate. Right? of this Indian
YouTuber that you're talking about. I'm
not sure who it is, but yeah, you will
see lots of people falling for these
these various kinds of PS whether it's a
so-called honey trap or whether it's
something else. Lots of Indians fall for
these things. And the truth is it's not
only Indians who fall for this. Even the
other side can be made to fall for it.
Okay.
Anyway, Duv Durya says, "Recently I saw
a video of the air chief, the air force
chief of India saying that we are not
able to deliver 40 as aircrafts in 8
years and I hope that statement of the
of the chief of the air force, the head
of the air force, it hopefully gave a
kick on the backside of those who are
supposed to manufacture those stages
aircrafts. Right. I hope so." He was
absolutely right. We need to gear up. We
need to ramp up our production. We
should be we should be manufacturing 40
TES fighter planes in one year, not 40
in 80
years. It's a question of the national
security, right? It's it's a question of
the nation's interests. So, I think it's
high time for whoever manufactures the
aircrafts, DRDO, HL, whoever it
is
to to to to, you know, do what they're
supposed to do. Do your job and do it
right.
Dibbos
says, "How come the Sukoy 57 is a fifth
generation fighter plane, but it's still
40% the cost of the
F-35?" The F3 The F-35 is an overpriced
piece of trash. It's an overpriced
flying trash
can. They have spent incredible amounts
of money to produce a substandard
aircraft. Now, I don't know how good or
bad the SU357 is. Maybe it doesn't have
all the great characteristics that the
the F-35 has, but the Russians want to
waste so much money. They don't have the
kind of money the Americans have. So,
obviously, they made it in a much better
way. Look, the com Let me give you an
appropriate comparison. the the the the
movie the Hollywood movie Gravity costs
cost $100 million to make but we sent a
spacecraft to Mars in less than the cost
of that one movie about uh it's a
science fiction movie about going to
space. So that's the kind of money the
Americans have compared to what we have.
So we can send an actual spacecraft to
Mars in less money than it costs to make
a Hollywood movie, right? So it's
possible. Anything's possible. I'm not
sure how good or bad the Suka 57 is, but
I'm I'm value for money wise, it's way
better, I'm sure, than the
F-35. Okay. Uh Savaria S says, "What are
the advantages of ballistic missiles
over cruise missiles?" Um okay, the rest
of it I don't know what it means. What's
the advantage of a ballistic missile
over a cruise missile? Cruise missiles
are like aircraft. It's like cruise
missiles are kind of you can think of a
cruise missile as being like a pilotless
aircraft. There's no human being inside
it. It's been given a target. It knows
where to go and it's on a suicide
mission. It's on a kamicazi mission. So,
it's going to go and slam into the
target and it's got a warhead which will
then explode. That's a cruise missile.
So, a cruise missile flies like an
aircraft. Okay? It flies at maybe
whatever altitude you want it to. maybe
10 km like a cruise like a regular
aircraft maybe it's a sea skimming
missile or ground hugging missile which
means it's maybe flying 50 ft above the
ground or if it's flying over the sea
maybe it's 20 ft above the sea or
something to keep a low profile and
evade radar detection but cruise
missiles typically fly much slower than
ballistic missiles a cruise missile if
it's a supersonic one like the bramos
it's mark 2.8 8 nearly almost three
times the speed of sound. If it's uh the
nearby no not the nearby the what is it
I think the nearby missile which is a
subsonic cruise missile well that would
fly slower than the speed of sound. So
each missile has a different role and
purpose. The advantage of a cruise
missile is that it can fly low and uh it
can remain undetected if detected. And
ballistic missiles they have a
completely different flight path. They
have a parabolic flight path and they
enter at extremely high they they
reenter the atmosphere after exit
exiting it at extremely high velocities.
So most nations don't have the
technological means to take out a
ballistic missile because it comes in so
fast. It reenters so fast. Cruise
missiles have a different flight path.
Ballistic missiles have a different
flight path and they used for different
means. The longest range of a cruise
missile may be like 3,000
uh I don't know 3,000 km maybe.
Typically cruise missiles have a range
of maybe for example certain versions of
the Brahos have a range of about 300 km.
Some versions of the bramos are rumored
to have a range of 1500 km. Rumored to.
Okay. And the Nirby seems to have a
range of 1200 or 1500 km and so on.
There may be longer range cruise
missiles. So cruise missiles have a
certain range beyond which you can't
they can't go. Ballistic missiles
depending on what you how much fuel and
whatever else you put into them can have
an intercontinental range. So you can
launch a ballistic missile from let's
say somewhere in India and you can have
it hit Antarctica hypothetically if you
want that's way way far away or any
other continent that you can imagine.
I'll not take names because it's a nasty
thing to say but that sort of thing. So
ballistic missiles have essentially in
almost unlimited range depending on how
much fuel etc you place into them and
the size of the missile and so on. So
that's the difference. Uh ballistic
missiles have advantages. Cruise
missiles have their own advantages. The
Russians have a certain weapon system
that they announced in 2019 which is a
nuclear fueled nuclear powered cruise
missile which is not the same as a
cruise missile with a nuclear warhead.
This uses nuclear power for propulsion
nuclear
propulsion. So it's got a nuclear
ramjet. The bramos has a ramjet but it's
got a chemical ramjet. This Russian
weapon system apparently cruise missile
has a apparently has a nuclearpowered
ramjet
ramjet. So it's got essentially
unlimited range. It can fly 20 times
around the world before hitting its
target if it wants to. It can loiter for
days possibly before it wants to. So
that's a different kind of cruise
missile. But that too is a cruise
missile. So missiles come in various
classes, various capabilities and so on
so forth. And depending on what your
objectives are, you can use other
ballistic missiles or crew missiles or
subsonic cruise missiles or supersonic
cruise missiles or hypersonic cruise
missiles. You can even use MIRV equipped
ballistic missiles to to ensure you
really strike a target. You can use MRV
equipped ballistic missiles, warheads
and so on. Lots of things. So it's it's
pretty complicated but uh it all depends
on what you want to achieve and who the
adversary is and what their uh air
defense capabilities are
like. Adwit says the media never shows
any headline that the US lost so and so
they had 7 to eight MQ9 Reaper drones,
three FA18s and F-16 and they almost
lost F-35 by the to the Houthis who are
not even professional soldiers. You see
the Americans lose equipment all the
time. They lose their most advanced
drones. They lose FA18 fighter planes.
They lose F-16s. They almost they they
even lose F-35s once in a while here and
there. But nobody makes a human cry
about that. But if the Pakistanis claim
that the so and so Indian aircraft came
down, then Indians start making a human
cry about this. Indians they lack a
proper perspective on the world that in
warfare you're going to have losses of
equipment. It's part of the game. It's
part of the deal. It's something you
have to absorb. It's something you have
to accept. If you can't take any loss in
in war, then you are not a nation that's
serious. That's not a nation that that
deserves success. And we are a nation
that deserves success. But the
population a significant population
percentage of the population has these
ideas that if we lose one
aircraft then no matter it doesn't
matter if we hit 20 Pakistani air bases
we lost one aircraft which means we we
the loser losers of the war that's the
kind of attitude Indians have Indians
are so easy to mentally manipulate by
the west so that's something that is a
huge deficiency in India Indians lack
self-confidence Indians have an
inferiority complex and it is not the
fault of the Indians that they are like
this. It's the education system that's
done this to them. The education system
has never inculcated any sense of pride
or self-confidence in the people of
India. That's why it's so easy to
mislead and manip and manipulate
Indians. So, Adwit is completely right.
See how much equipment the Americans
have lost in the last few months. But no
one speaks about
that,
right? I will I will take no more
questions about the alleged Rafal
thing.
Um Raf says, "What about the nuclear
warheads that went missing from us?" I
can assure you none of our nuclear
warheads are missing.
I don't know what you've heard of and
where you heard heard it from, but I can
assure you that none of our nuclear
warheads are missing.
Right. Um, okay. Aramana says after
India destroyed the Chinese air defense
system, now the quality of Chinese air
defense has been exposed to the world.
Will China is China going to do some
mischievous acts against us? I mean,
they can try if they want to. What can
they do? Uh, it's not our fault that
their air defense systems and radars are
substandard. It's not our fault,
right? If they had done the job they
were supposed to do, then maybe we would
have we would have had a tougher tougher
time in the three-day war against
Pakistan. So, we had no ill intentions
towards Pakistan, towards China.
It's China's own fault that their
systems did not work. Right? So they if
they are upset they need to
introspect. Apparently they had sold
their best air defense systems to the
Pakistanis and see what happened. I
think they should be very worried if
they had any plans of going to war with
India or or trying to test India's
capabilities. Uh so it's it's entirely
their fault whatever's happened right
and if they want to do something
mischievous against us well they can try
and apparently it looks like our
technology is is superior to theirs so
they can try. Yeah, they're welcome to,
I would
say.
Uh, right
now the Scrummer 1989 says, "Instead of
humans, can we use robots on the
warfronts? Are our organizations taking
any steps towards making this a
possibility?"
uh considering what we have seen during
the 3-day special military operation
against Pakistan operation zindur I
think it's quite possible that we have
organizations that are doing all kinds
of stuff but away from the the public
eye it's possible that we are doing
stuff that we are uh taking steps in
various directions that involve robotics
and AI and such systems it's very
possible we have the best minds in the
world. No question about it. Right? So,
it's certainly possible. It's certainly
going to happen in the future. It's
going to be increasingly the case that
we're going to have more and more
robotic systems and AI enabled systems
in the battlefield.
And eventually maybe in 10 years maybe
maybe before that maybe later eventually
you may have wars that are fought
entirely between robotic armies it's
possible be going in that direction. So
right now if you see the advances in
robotics uh you have robots that can now
stack shelves in in commercial
establishments. For example, if you have
a warehouse like let's say an Amazon
warehouse or something, then robots can
stack the shelves and transport one
bundle from another and one package from
another another one place to another and
so on. Robots can do that. Robots are
increasingly able to do things that
humans can do. And very soon you're
going to have warehouses that are
entirely staffed by robots, not a single
human being because robots typically
they don't make mistakes. Humans get
tired and they they can lose
concentration or have lapses of
concentration or if you're in a bad mood
you will you you can make more mistakes
and so on. Robots don't have that issue.
Right? So very soon we're going to have
warehouses and and other things
establishments like that that are
entirely operated by robots. Similarly
the same thing will happen in in in the
battlefield. You're going to have robot
soldiers. You're going to have robot
dogs. You're going to have robotic
drones. You're going to have AI enabled
systems. It's all going to happen. We
are going in that direction and I'm
pretty sure after what I've seen the in
the 3-day military operation against
Pakistan that we are taking this
extremely seriously we as in India. So
yeah I'm now pretty confident let's not
be all confident but yeah I think we
we're going on the right in the right
direction in the right direction.
Now Shri Ramachandraan Namaha says how
is India using the Anderman and Nikobar
islands to make it a naval power and air
force
base. Um
well what are we doing? I think we have
we are constructing a big port a trans
shshipment facility in the Adabar and
Nikkob Islands. That's one thing we're
doing. We have probably if I mean
anybody can see this. We haven't opened
the map today. It's been 1 hour 35
minutes. I haven't opened the map.
What's going on these days? Let's take a
look at what's available in the public
domain. So I am only showing what's what
anybody can see. Okay? I'm not showing
any secrets. Anybody can see this. So So
that's why therefore it is fine to show
what I'm showing. This is not a secret.
Uh let's look at for example the little
Anderman. What do we have here? the
little Anderman Islands. I don't see too
much action activity happening
here. Typically, you want to see
something that's visible from a
distance. So, not much happening here.
Little Andaman. What do we have here?
This is South Sentinel Island. Uh,
that's not the one. Now, we have this is
Indonesia now. So, we have gone too far
south. Indonesia is what? Indonesia is
about one less than 150 km from India.
neighboring nation. Now let's look at a
large and man or whatever you want to
call it. What do we have going on
here? So let us see. Let us see. I'm
sure this
uh I'm sure we have air force etc
capabilities here somewhere here. I can
see an aircraft airport over here. This
is obviously an international airport,
Vir Sawker International Airport. And uh
it's possible it may have some air force
aircraft also, which is okay. Which is
okay. Uh what else? Um
Sithur and so on. I've heard of
something called Campbell Bay, right?
One second. I don't know why it is
foreign names.
Campbell Bay and the Wandabar Islands.
Zoomed in right away. Where is
this? Okay, fine. It's over here. So, I
think I went too far north. I missed
Campbell Bay. So, we have an airport
here as well. Uh, is this an
international airport? Is it a domestic
airport? What's the distance? What's the
length of the runway? 1.26 km. Not a
very big
runway, excuse me. And so on. This is a
nice bay that we have. Uh I'm sure it
will make a very good naval base if you
want to and so on. So we have some
capabilities over here in the Anderman
and islands. I think we have not really
done enough to leverage the incredible
geographical location that these islands
uh represent. Um but I'm sure that we
are doing something or the other to uh
leverage its position. The Anderman and
Nikoma Islands can serve as an
unsinkable aircraft carrier. You can
have air force bases there for sure. You
can have naval bases there. You can even
have submarine bases there. It It's not
a bad idea to have maybe 100 200 fighter
planes stationed over there. Maybe 100,
maybe a few submarines, 10 20
submarines. Of course, we only have 16
or so submarines, so we need to do
something about that. But yeah, it's
it's a it's a
tremendously important tremendously
strategic
uh location, geographical location in
the middle of the eastern Indian Ocean,
the so-called Bay of Bengal. Right? So I
think India is doing something about it.
I think India should do a lot more about
that. A lot more needs to be done and
can be done.
Um okay Navin Kubar says why did the
Chinese air defense system fail so
miserably in this Indopak war is was
there a problem with this with the
quality of the system or was there a
issue with the skills of the Pakistanis
operating it I can't say I can't say for
sure
uh you can only tell if you were there
and you you saw what was what was being
done with the system
I would not want to blame the Pakistani
skills on this. I'm sure the Pakistani
military has reasonably competent
people. I know we we all know they are
terrorists. They have this hatred
towards India and they have this love
for terrorism. We know that. But I think
the Pakistani military is reasonably
competent and I would not imagine that
they would have unskilled people. I'm
sure they have reasonably skilled people
who operate whatever they they operate,
right? Um, and that's why I don't I
would not blame this on the skills of
the Pakistanis operating the Chinese air
defense system. I would blame this on
the on on the Chinese technology. I
think the Chinese technology is
substandard. That's what it looks like.
That's what I think has happened. And
that's a big problem for for China.
They're going to be very worried now. If
they thought that there would have been
some kind of u some kind of uh advantage
that they have visav India and maybe
that advantage will give them the
opportunity to maybe indulge in a war
with India. Yeah. Hypothetically along
the India Tibet border undemared border
or something. Now they'll be worried
about it. Now they will not consider the
possibility of a war even if they have
so-called stealth aircraft or semi-
stealth aircraft like like the J20 or
whatever. Uh the J20 is rumored to be
reasonably well stealthy from the front,
but its backside apparently is not
stealthy at all or or it's it's got
minimal stealth issues or whatever. So I
don't think the Chinese will be happy
about what's happened now. And uh
considering the fact that our air
defenses are so good, the Akash system
and the the fact that their air defenses
are terrible and the radars don't work,
they're going to be worried now. And
there's now you see that gives us a
position of strength comparatively. Of
course they still are a very powerful
nation much more powerful than us. We
cannot become overconfident but yep it's
a it's a interesting development for
sure. Chiag says uh there was so much of
a delta between 2019 and 2025 operation
Synindur. Is it mainly because of
economic growth? Does it have any other
factor? It's an interesting question.
Shira asks us. Let's compare the 2019
Balakot event with the 2025 operation
Sindur event.
2019 we launched an air strike deep
inside Pakistan in the Kyber Pakuna
province I think it was that province
Balakort and there was a terrorist
headquarters or or
or hideout or whatever it was over
there. So we launched an air strike. We
used spice bombs. We hit the terror
center and apparently a bunch of
terrorists died. But
but we produced no evidence. We did not
have drones at the time. Apparently as
far as I know. So we were not able to
send a drone to Pakistan to to fly over
Balakot and film the strikes and show
that you know we actually did that and
we actually hid the place. We produced
no such evidence in Balakot. That's
number one. Number two, you can say
reason with a reasonable amount of truth
that at
least that that we were kind of out
outmaneuvered from an air force
perspective because one of our fighter
planes went into Pakistani airspace or
Pakistani occupied airspace and was shot
down.
We shot down an F-16 but we were able to
provide no evidence of that.
And our fighter plane was shot down over
Pakistani occupied territory and one of
our pilots was captured by Pakistan.
Right? And so that's number two. We used
MIG 21s. We had a pilot who was captured
then there to return him. And
thirdly, we shot down one of our own
helicopters. Right? These are the things
that happened in 2019.
Now look at
2025. See the incredible difference
between 29 2019 in
2025. 25 and 20 20 2019 night and day
difference. We did not use Mig 21s. I
don't know which fighter planes we used
but we did not use Mig 21s. We used
drones to incredibly great effect. We
used missiles of various kinds. I don't
know which missiles but the Pakistanis
had no answer to the missiles. We wiped
out their air
defenses. Um we used drones of various
kinds. They tried to hit us over and
over and over again. In one night they
launched more than 500 drones at various
Indian cities all the way from Lei in
the north northern part of India all the
way to Sil Creek and Katch in the in the
southern part of the India Pakistan
border they could not hit a single
Indian city they could not hit a single
Indian air base they were able to hit
civilian areas because you can't defend
everything they were able to hit Punch
and Rajori with their shelling and
artillery fire or whatever it was right
but beyond that they could not hit a
single high value Indian military
installation
They tried launching a ballistic missile
or long long range missile at Delhi.
There also was brought down. I mean the
the difference between 2019 and 2025 is
a night and day difference. And then and
then in a matter of 30 less than 30
minutes, we hit 11 Pakistani air bases.
We hit them where it hurts the most. We
were able to hit Kirana Hills where they
are hiding nuclear
warheads. We were able to hit Saroda. We
were able to score direct hits on Nurh
Khan air base. We hit them in the heart
of Rahul, Pindi, Islamabad, everywhere
else. Pakistan, the Pakistanis had no
answer. Night and day difference,
incredible
difference. If you compare 2019 with 20
25, 2019 almost looks like a failure. It
was not. But comparatively what we
achieved in 25, you can't compare 2019
with it. 2019 also was a success but not
the kind of success we have seen in
2025. Why did we have the
success? Because first of all we learned
the lessons of
2019. We had certain deficiencies in
2019. We have rectified all the
deficiencies. We are now using
cuttingedge fighter planes. Apparently
we definitely I'm sure did not use Mig21
this time. We have
uh embraced 21st century warfare drone
warfare. We also have anti- drone
systems, anti-missile and other things
systems, incredible air defense. So we
have used a lot of indigenous systems.
The Harop drone may be of Israeli design
but we manufacture it in India. The
Akash system is of Indian design and
manufactured in India. And the L70 gun
we have enhanced and augmented it and
turned it turned it into a tremendously
uh potent air defense weapon. And we
have other systems as well.
So because of our own R&D because of
because we have trusted our own
engineers and scientists and technicians
because we have inducted our own systems
that's why that's one reason why we have
succeeded uh we have embraced AI
possibly we have embraced robotics we've
embraced drone warfare and all of this
happens why how has all of this happened
because obviously of economic growth the
more the larger your economy is the more
you can spend on the military and u
that's one. Number two, leadership. You
may have a great economy, but if your
leadership isn't isn't good, then the
that the military will not get what it
needs. So leadership is very important.
So I'm sure a lot of the credit has to
go to Prime Minister Mr. Modi, Narendra
Modi. Um imagine if you had AK Anthony
as the defense minister today, would we
have dealt with Pakistan this
way? Think about it.
So yeah, these are the reasons why
there's such a huge delta as you say
between 2019 and
2025.
Um, all
right. Knowledge seeker one says, "Was
Trump scared that he was going to lose
the trade war because China would sell
weapons and get out of a bad financial
situation?" Trump trying to is Trump
trying to pressure India into a trade
deal now? How can Trump lose a trade
war? Because China will sell weapons. To
whom will they sell
weapons to get out of the bad financial
situation? They would need maybe a
trillion dollars of weapon sales to
sales. To whom will they sell that much
weaponry to Pakistan? Do you think
Pakistan has any money to give to
China? Uh that's not how it works, my
friends. Uh is Trump trying to pressure
India to trade deal into a trade deal
now? of of course he's trying to
pressure India into trade deal. He wants
India to have 0% tariffs on the on the
United States which means the Americans
can flood the Indian market with their
goods. That's what he wants. And if we
don't agree to a 0% trade deal, then
they will impose tariffs on us. Well,
let's see how it goes. If he is going to
be
unreasonable, let it be. Right. Right.
Samat asks a very pertinent question.
Should India increase defense spending?
Now I think India needs to definitely
increase defense spending. I don't know
what percentage of our GDP goes into
into the defense budget. Maybe it's 2%,
maybe it's 2.5%. I'm not sure. Maybe
it's less than 2%. I'm not really sure.
I haven't seen the latest figures.
uh but a significant percentage of the
defense budget goes into simply paying
salaries and pensions of uh current
armed forces personnel and retired armed
forces
personnel. So how much of the defense
budget actually goes
into maintaining weapons and buying new
weapon systems? Not a lot. I think India
should double its defense budget for the
next 10 years. Get serious. The world is
now pretty nasty place. Wars erupting
everywhere. You got China on one side,
Pakistan on on the other side. You got
East Pakistan, West Pakistan on two on
the east and west of India. To the
northern part of India, you have this
huge undemarcated border with Chinese
occupied
Tibet. Then you have various projects
like project K, Cookie Land for Christ
to create a new artificial Christian
nation cookie land out of parts of
Manipur, Misoram, Bangladesh and
Myanmar. Myanmar has been destabilized
by the Biden Biden regime. The cookie
land for Christ project K was a Biden
regime creation. Right? We have so much
so many
threats. It is time I think India should
double its defense budget for maybe 10
years. India needs to arm itself to the
teeth really. Considering the
neighborhood we living in, considering
the kind of the the kind of neighbors
the gods have gifted us today. I don't
blame the gods for it. But whatever it
is, you know, we need to take our
defense much more
seriously. Excuse
me. Ragunat says, "Is next war over
Industry coming soon?" Do you think?
Yes. So the the Pakistanis have claimed
that the Indust treaty abrogation is
like an act of war. My question to the
Pakistanis are is okay, let's say it's
an act of war. What can you do about it?
What are you going to do about it? You
have hit us over and over again for
decades with terrorism and we choose not
to do a thing about it. Now we said
enough is
enough. Water and blood cannot flow
together. So we're going to abrogate the
industry until you guys
prove demonstrate to the world and to
us. Forget about the world to you
demonstrate to
us that you have actually shut down your
terror factories and dismantled all your
terror infrastructure and eliminated all
your terrorists. Until you give us
incontrovertible proof of all of this,
we not going to honor the Industry team.
As as simple as that. Now, if you have a
problem with that, do your worst. Do
what you can. you do a terror strike
against India, we will take it as an act
of war and we're going to treat you as
war criminals and operation Synindhur
will will look like just a trailer of
what's really going to
come. So the question really is is
Pakistan in a position to go to war with
India. What are their capabilities? They
are in no position to go to war with
India. The worst thing they can do is to
strike at India through asymmetric
warfare which means terror strikes.
That is something that we would take
very very seriously. And if there is a
terror strike anywhere in India, the
Pakistanis must pay for it very badly.
Very
badly.
Uh okay. Tina Yadav says Trump
trumpet Trumpet Trump asked Tim Cook to
not manufacture in India. Why is he in
why is he so insecure all of a sudden?
and IAEA denied the nuclear leak. So I
discussed what Trump said some time ago.
Uh he is upset that India has uh hit his
pet terrorist nation so hard. Trump
seems to have a great fodness for
terrorists. He recently met with Al
Jolani, a terrorist with a $10 million
bounty on his head from the FBI. Uh so
he seems to be completely okay with
professional head choppers.
Golani was a professional head chopper
just a few years ago. Um so Trump is
okay with that. The Americans have a
track record of being very comfortable
with terrorists and human rights
abusers. Of course they they sponsored
these people, funded and financed these
people. So it's fine. So Trump is
unhappy that we have hit Pakistan so
badly. And he's unhappy that we are
negotiating hard when it comes to the
trade and tariff deal. Right? We are not
allowing the Americans to arm twist us
and push us over. It's not working. So
Trump is very unhappy. It's not only
Pakistan, it's also the trade thing. He
wants India to have zero a zero tariff
policy when it comes to American goods.
That is uh
unreasonable, right? So it's not going
well and that's why he's unhappy. So
that's that's the reason why he is doing
all this and he's you know heaping
praise on Pakistan these days.
Pakistanis are a fantastic people and
Pakistan makes wonderful things. What
wonderful things is what what what
wonderful things does Pakistan make. The
only wonder only high quality thing the
Pakistanis make is
terrorists. So I don't know now IAEA
dire nuclear leak. I don't know about
that. Um I'm I've not heard the news of
the
international atomic whatever
agency what they may or may not have
said about Pakistan and the possible
nuclear leak I don't
know and if they say something we don't
have to trust them it's not like if
somebody says something they are telling
the truth all the time right all these
agencies are um are tools in the hands
of the west to be used for various
purposes When the WH
says, what's his name? Dr.
Tedros, do you think if he says
something you should trust
him? What was that thing called? O
Micron. Oh Micron. I mean, where is the
Corona virus today? It was such a big
deal, right? They shut down the entire
world for the Corona virus. That's how
dangerous it apparently
was. Where is it today? They said it it
it came from I don't know what it was a
natural thing. By now I think it's
pretty well established that the corona
virus was a bioweapon. So these people
they have been lying. They have a habit
of lying and they will use lies to
mislead people. So maybe there's a
nuclear leak in Pakistan. But to to
cover it up they are lying once again.
It's that's also a possibility we have
to consider. So my point my perspective
is that I don't trust any of these
people. I know for a fact that they use
fake news and propaganda to mislead the
world. They've done this over and over
again. They've been doing it for
decades and there's no reason for us to
believe
them.
Okay.
Um Anul says, "How good is the Indian
army's Kali weapon? TV channel Network
18, which is the umbrella corporation
for CNN News and News8 is owned by
Reliance. Why is the government not
using Motavi for information warfare?
Okay, there are like three different
questions. I am not aware of this Kali
weapon. I've heard rumors of it for the
past for more than 20
years.
Um it's some kind of allegedly some kind
of directed energy weapon. I'm sure we
have directed energy weapons also called
lasers also uh lasers, measors,
microwave weapons, whatever you want to
call them, directed energy weapons. I
think we we re our uh one of our
research organizations recently tested a
very powerful directed energy weapon
probably more powerful than what the
Americans have publicly announced that
they
have. So is this the Kali weapon that
people have been talking about? I'm not
sure. So when it comes to directed
energy
weapons, I think we probably have a
pretty good research and development uh
set of projects that may be ongoing.
So yeah, when you're saying Kali weapon,
you you mean directed energy weapon or
or laser weapon. I think we are pretty
good on that front. I'm not sure if we
have actually uh deployed it with our
armed forces. I'm not sure if that's the
case, but I'm pretty sure that we are in
the process of doing the R&D, the
development of such weapons and uh at an
appropriate time they will be inducted
into the armed forces whenever it is
appropriate, whenever it is well tested.
So it'll happen. So I'm pretty confident
we are on good ground when it comes to
directed energy weapons. So the
advantage of a directed energy weapon.
Let's understand what that is. Let's say
you have incoming missiles. H so we saw
the Pakistanis launched hundreds of
drones and god knows how many missiles
at us at more than 20 Indian cities more
than more than 25 Indian cities. And we
defended these our cities and our people
and our military installations from
these Pakistani missiles and drones and
whatnot.
We defended using a multi-layered multi-
u multi-layered air defense system which
had the L70 gun which had the pora
system which had the Akash system
possibly the barak system and also the
S400 system right so when you want to
bring down an incoming drone you have to
shoot something at it the L70 gun will
shoot some kind of shell at the incoming
drone Right? And it's very accurate. So
it hits. Now there, let's say there's a
missile coming in. So you use something
else to shoot down the missile. But
instead of using projectiles like shells
or missiles or whatever, what if you use
energy? Just
energy. So that's a directed energy
weapon. energy in the form of light,
photons, laser,
uh light amplification by stimulated
emission of radiation. That's laser. So
essentially you have extremely focused
an extremely focused light beam
completely coherent and it contains a
huge amount of energy that can take out
anything from a from any distance that
you want. uh not any distance but yeah
you you get what I mean so it's much
more effective it's even more accurate
than anything we may currently have but
it consumes a lot of energy that's why
it's very difficult to miniaturaturize
such systems and that's the game uh so
that's a directed energy weapon or laser
weapon and I think we are doing good on
that front now about the propaganda
thing I'm sure the government can do
better than what it's doing right now
for
Um, geopolitical dubet says Elon Musk
today is enjoying the privileges, but
after but what after the Trump regime?
Don't you think the Democrats will do
everything possible to hunt him
down? Maybe by the time he'll be on
Mars. Who knows? See, Trump uh sorry, uh
Musk is the world's richest man today,
as far as I know. uh a net worth of more
than $400
billion.
Um and he is
very central in in some ways to uh the
promotion of America's geopolitical
interest interests especially in the
dimension in the domain of space in the
domain of terrestrial surveillance
through satellite networks and so on
and interference in in in the internal
affairs of nations through Twitter
through through X and also by spying on
nations via satellites and by beaming
satellite internet where nations may not
want internet to be there and so on.
He's integral to the US geopolitical
interests and it makes no sense for
Democrats if they come to power in the
future to go after Elon Musk because he
is integral to the interests of their
nation which is their interests. Uh so I
don't think it's going to go it's going
to play out in that ma in that manner.
When it comes to his relationship with
Trump I don't think it'll last that
long. You know, Trump is a very egoistic
person, right? We know that. Very vain
person, very self-centered person, kind
of a narcissist, very egoistic,
self-centered. It's all about me, me
first, me first, and so on. That's
that's the sort of guy Trump
is.
And and you can and and and we know that
Elon Musk is richer than Trump. Elon
Musk is more successful than Trump. Elon
Musk in the long run may end up being
more powerful than Trump. And Trump
can't stand that. So I don't think this
relationship will last very long. I
think Elon Musk has already been asked
to vacate the office he had in the White
House and go back to where he was. And I
think he's kind of stepping back from
his political activities. So that was
bound to happen, right? And in the long
run, I don't think Democrats will do
every possible thing to hunt him down.
He's he's just too important for the
nation.
Vikram Suman Vikrram Vikrant Panda says
can India intercept a nuclear missile if
it is shot down over our land over our
land how is radiation risk handled India
I think most likely can hand intercept a
nuclear missile it's possible I mean the
Pakistanis launched a long range missile
at Delhi we know that it was brought
down over Hana they launched a long
range missile possibly that Fata or
whatever they call it with a range of
400 km which is no longer a short range
missile. We brought it down.
Now there's no difference between a
regular missile and a nuclear
missile. It's the same missile but if
you put a nuclear warhead inside it then
it's a nuclear missile. So the
propulsion system is the same. The
missile is the same. The only thing
that's that changes is instead of a
conventional chemical warhead you put a
nuclear warhead. That's the only
difference. The warhead, the warhead is
the only difference. The missile is the
same thing. So if you can intercept the
missile that they launched at
Delhi, then you can intercept the
nuclear missiles. I I'm not sure they
tried ballistic missiles. I don't think
it was a ballistic missile that was
brought down over Hana. It was long
range missile, the Fataya or whatever
the hell they call it. So we definitely
can intercept that. We can intercept all
the things that they threw at us during
the course of the three-day war.
We also have the Pritwi air defense
system which is designed to take out
ballistic missiles incoming ballistic
missiles. So the pritu air defense
system has a two twopronged approach. It
has two interceptor missiles. The first
interceptor missile it takes uh it it
intercepts the incoming ballistic
missile outside of the atmosphere that
is more than 100 kilometers from the
surface of the earth. it takes out the
incoming ballistic missile at an
altitude of more than 100 km. Now in
case for whatever reason that missile
fails to intercept the incoming
ballistic missile and the sec second
missile is launched which then
intercepts the incoming missile at an
altitude of about 60 50 40 km above the
earth's surface. So it's two missiles
that are launched. If the first one
doesn't work the second one will do its
job and uh it's pretty clear that
India's missiles are extremely accurate.
We even have the ASAT system which can
take out incoming ballistic
missiles, right? It can take out objects
that are traveling at more than mark
25. So India I I think we need not be
worried about India's capabilities
u of of defending the country against
ballistic missiles or incoming threats
of various kinds. I think I'm I'm
I'm actually shocked at how surprised at
how good at how good our air defense
system is. So yeah, I think India can
certainly India I think already has the
capability to capabilities to intercept
incoming ballistic missiles, nuclear
missiles, whatever you want to call
them. Now if a missile is shot down over
our territory, how is the radiation risk
handled? So you have to
understand let's say you have a
plutonium warhead. There are two kinds
of nuclear warheads. A nuclear warhead
is the actual bomb okay which is uh put
inside in the front fairing of a
missile. So the nuclear warhead the bomb
if it's a if if if the facile material
used in that is plutonium
then it will the the plutonium will be
about 5 kilos maybe. I'm giving you a
very rough ballpark figure. I'm not
giving you exact numbers. Roughly 5
kilos, maybe 10 kilos at most. If it's
uranium, it could be 20, 30 kilos, maybe
kilos. So, it makes sense to use
plutonium because it it has Yeah, it's
better to in handling and all that. So,
let's say you have a plutonium warhead
maybe 10 kilos of plutonium. You don't
understand that plutonium is not a
powder. Plutonium is a metal.
it's a metal. If it's not plutonium and
it's uranium, then once again, uranium
is not a powder, it's a metal. So, if
you destroy a warhead, you take it down,
then the warhead may not explode, it'll
just
break. Or maybe it's designed that if
it's taken down, it'll explode in the
air, then it's okay. It explodes like 50
km above the air. Or maybe it explodes
uh outside of the atmosphere. Doesn't
make much of a difference to us. There
have been so many atmospheric nuclear
tests in the past.
so many atmospheric nuclear tests it
makes it it did not make any difference
much of a difference to the world. So if
it explodes in the air, let's say, no
big deal. But if it fails to explode and
comes down on the earth, then you have
to hunt for a few pieces of uranium or
plutonium. That's it. It doesn't cause a
tremendous amount of contamination or
fallout, nuclear fallout, radioactive
fallout. Radioactive fallout happens
when a nuclear reactor
uh malfunctions and and uh suffers
meltdown maybe explosive meltdown like
what happened in Chernobyl what happened
in
Fukushma but when it comes to nuclear
warheads malfunctioning or or being
destroyed or exploding you won't have
that sort of scenario so we need not be
worried about this too
much okay Um Prit Pritam Gurong says the
Indian Air Force have also said that
they have used UAVs that mimic jets
under radar signature dummy jets to
engage bait and fooled Chinese air
defense systems. Good job.
I I I I am very pleased to hear this. I
approve of this. What else can I say?
Absolutely good. Absolutely brilliant.
Outstanding.
Um All right.
Um okay being chilling bling chilling
says how chi no has China have China and
the US agreed to not let a third power
grow also why don't we see internal
India infra roads grow despite economic
growth or will it start eventually like
how it was with China I think the US and
China have some kind of understanding
okay we are adversaries we are nearpeer
competitors China is like not as
entirely a peer of the But yeah, you
could consider these to be to be the
most consequential nations today. I am
pretty sure the US and Chinese have an
understanding. Let's let's compete with
each other, but let's not allow a third
power to emerge and grow. So I think the
US and the Chinese I think they see very
much eye to eye when it comes to India.
Neither wants India to grow.
The US is happy to use India if possible
for them as a pawn against China but not
at the cost of having India grow and
becoming more powerful. They would not
like to see that and you can see you can
see their approach when it came to India
almost destroying Pakistan, you know. So
yeah, I think they have an understanding
about India. Let's not let's not
tolerate India growing. Let's keep it
let's cut India down to size if possible
and prevent it from growing. uh I think
they have the agreement that
understanding now why don't we see uh
internal growth infrastructure in India
and so on despite economic growth I
think we are seeing that
um I know that we would like to see it
in cities but I think what we are seeing
is the construction of tremendous
quantities of highways railways airports
all of that is happening so that's what
see when it comes to the construction
construction and deployment of
infrastructure uh the central government
doesn't have that much role that much of
a role to play except in building
highways, uh, railways, air airports and
so on. That's what the central
government does. When it comes to, uh,
improving the living standards in
cities, all that comes under state
governments. And some in some states,
you will see better living standards
than other states. I mean, some states
uh have vastly better living standards
than the states that are
economically bigger than them.
I'll not take names because it'll upset
people. But yeah, you go to some states
living standards are way better than
other states which apparently have a
bigger GDP than the state where they
than when where stuff is better. So I
think it all of that is a it comes under
state state governments and it's for the
state governments to answer their
citizens as to why things aren't good
compared to that state or their state
right
uh yeah that that's an issue in India
for sure that's an issue things can be
so much
better uh Tina Yadav says have you seen
the meme center of gravity I I'm hearing
a lot of people making fun of this meme
but I haven't seen it myself so maybe
after this is over I'll go to Twitter or
somewhere and look up center of gravity
ity. I haven't seen that. I I get the
feeling it's something very
funny.
Uh okay. Dunca says if plutonium and
uranium are metals, which they are,
which they are. If you don't believe me,
let me um demonstrate to you what
plutonium and uranium look like, then
I'll answer your question. So, let's go
to our good old friend
Google. Google plutonium.
Plutonium. What does plutonium look
like? Right? That's the question. What's
it look like? See, this is plutonium. As
you can see, it's a metal. Here,
plutonium is behaving differently.
Here's
plutonium. And so on. So, plutonium is a
metal. All right. This is what plutonium
looks like. This is what plutonium looks
like. It's a metal. What about uranium?
It's another another
metal. There you have it. This is the
ore but this is the actual purified
uranium. Here you have uranium ore,
uranium yellow cake which is processed
ore, uranium hexof hexaflloride gas,
dioxide which is like dark. Then you
have fuel pellets and so on and so
forth. That's uranium. So, so uh
hopefully it's clear that both uranium
and plutonium are metals. All right. Now
the question you asked I think it's a
good question. Why don't we use it to
create structures, construction
machines, etc.? Yeah, because it is
radioactive. Because it's radioactive.
You are exposed. If you are exposed to
it for more than a few seconds, you are
pretty much guaranteed to have DNA
damage. And DNA damage, what is it
called? It's called
cancer. So, you don't want to be
anywhere near plutonium or uranium
without having a lead, a lead shield
between you and the metal. So that's the
reason why we do not want uranium
plutonium anywhere
uh to be used in any kind of
construction. Secondly, plutonium is a
shockingly powerful poison. I don't want
to tell you how poisonous plutonium is
and how it can be
misused. It is one of the most potent
poisons you can imagine. So you can't
have plutonium anywhere near you know
human habitations or or where human
beings
are. Okay.
Um what what else do we have? Apurva
says do you think India diplomatically
lost? No reaction by authorities on I'm
not taking any more Rafal
questions. India has not lost
diplomatically. The Pakistanis will lie.
The west will lie. We haven't lost
diplomatically and I'm not taking any
more Rafal questions. Rajor Shrigon says
some Indian YouTubers and influencers
are now under the radar of suspicion for
spying for Pakistan. If true, how can
they help apart from providing pics and
videos and of assets of concern? I am
not sure. Let's say you are a defense
YouTuber and you have access to the
Indian defense establishment to some
extent. Maybe you could do something.
I'm not sure. Okay. The main thing that
YouTubers who or influencers who are
compromised, the main thing they can do
is create the wrong narrative, the wrong
perception and maybe create
proakistan narratives and push
proakistan narratives. That's the main
thing you can do. But there's no law
against that, right? Because India has a
freedom of speech and all that nonsense.
And that's why many big YouTubers and
all these individuals have a what you
could call an antinational approach.
Um yeah so I don't think you see you
cannot spy for a country unless you have
access to to sensitive places and and
classified information. If you don't
have access to sensitive places and
classified information you can't spy but
you can
certainly push a propaganda narrative
that is pro Pakistan. That's the kind of
thing you can do. So many of these
influencers YouTubers do that. We know
that very well. So that's how it goes.
Uh, okay. With that question, I'm going
to come to the end of today's live
stream. We have again crossed 2 hours 15
minutes. So, I'm going to end it over
here. Looks like the war is on a pause
right now. The borders are no longer
hot. But let's see how long that
continues. But as as far as Pakistan
keeps on existing, we're going to be a
nation that's under threat because
Pakistan is a terrorist nation. And the
only way the threat will end is if we
once and for once and for all
comprehensively defeat Pakistan and
balkcanize it. I have nothing against
the people of Pakistan but the fact is
that most people most Pakistani people
want us dead. So sorry but not sorry. So
hopefully this happens soon. But the day
the pahelam attack happened the clock
started ticking backwards of Pakistan.
Hopefully soon. All right, end of
today's live stream. Thank you so much
for your questions and I will see you
very soon in the next next live stream.
Keep asking questions, keep raising your
standards and I'll see you very soon.
Take care. Bye-bye.